<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<TranslationTable_XML xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <!-- Misc: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>SlateScientist5_Were the structures on Dark Bramble always there?</key>
    <value>闇のイバラの構造物は以前からずっとあったのか？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>ScientistAnswerNEW_Well... yeah.</key>
    <value>えぇと、...ああ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>ScientistAnswerNEW_You know the little Anglerfish in the Museum? It got caught on the landing gear of one of our ships when it was flying close to get a good look at the structures, remember?</key>
    <value>博物館にある小型のアンコウは知っているよな？アイツは、あの構造物をよく見ようと近くを飛行していたときに探査艇の着陸装置に引っかかったんだが、...覚えているよな？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>ScientistAnswerNEW_...I think you need to wake up a bit from your pre-launch campout. Do a couple of jumps, maybe.</key>
    <value>...私が思うに、出発前のキャンプから少し目を覚ます必要があるな。ジャンプを2回くらいしてみたらどうだ？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_Trip 4, entry #... who cares. Crashes: 2. Boring crashes: 0.</key>
    <value>トリップ4、エントリーNo…誰が気にする？墜落:2 うんざりするような墜落:0</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_Well Dark Bramble, here I am! Saw what I though were two crashed ships over there, but it sorta looks intentional?</key>
    <value>そう、闇のイバラ、ここに私はいる！向こうに壊れた2つの船が見えたが、あれはどうやら意図的なものに見えるな？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_One looks Nomaian but the other one I’ve got no clue.</key>
    <value>1つはNomaiのものだが、もう1つはさっぱりわからない。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_I had a wander around, using these walkways. It’s quite peaceful, ignoring the Dark Bramble-y-ness of it all.</key>
    <value>ここの歩道を使ってぶらついてみた。なかなか平和な感じじゃないか、闇のイバラっぽさを無視すれば。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_Some places I couldn’t get into - I have some ideas, so if anyone is listening to this and wants some help, come chat with me.</key>
    <value>いくつか入れなかった場所があるものの―アイデアがある。もしこれを聞いていて、何か助言が欲しいなら私を訪ねるといい。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_...After I return, that is. Well, unless you’re as mad as I am, and want to come find me inside Dark Bramble!</key>
    <value>…私が戻った後、にはなる。まあ、お前が私と同じように狂っていて、闇のイバラ内部で私を見つけに来るのでなければな！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FeldsparRecording_Anyway, off inside I go! To adventure!</key>
    <value>とにかく、私は中へ行く！冒険へ！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Bramble Power Station</key>
    <value>イバラ動力ステーション</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Northern Observatory</key>
    <value>北部観測所</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Study Tower and Projection Pool House</key>
    <value>研究塔とプロジェクションプールの家</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Projection Pool House</key>
    <value>プロジェクションプールの家</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Bramble Village</key>
    <value>イバラの村</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Initial Campsite and Shuttle Crusher</key>
    <value>初期キャンプ場とシャトル破砕機</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Anglerfish Hunting Blind</key>
    <value>アンコウハントの隠れ家</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Misc: End -->
  <!-- Secret Poem: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>FRIEND: Failure of communication,</key>
    <value>FRIEND:意思伝達の失敗、</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FRIEND: Made worse by long duration.</key>
    <value>FRIEND:長い期間を経て悪化の一途をたどる。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FRIEND: In our minds, meaning of words undergo mutation,</key>
    <value>FRIEND:私たちの心の中で、言葉の意味は変化を遂げていき、</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FRIEND: Until we live in worlds of fabrication.</key>
    <value>FRIEND:偽りの世界で生きていくまで。</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Secret Poem: End (You can check hidden meaning of this poem in `darkbundle` file.) -->
  <!-- Bramble Station: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Wooooooo! Finally finished building this stupid space station!</key>
    <value>DATURA:うおーーーー！ついにこのバカげた宇宙ステーションを作り上げたぞ！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Couldn’t have done it without you Friend! (And your ship!)</key>
    <value>DATURA:君がいなかったらできなかったことだ、Friend！(あと君の船もだ！)</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: These seed things are great! Saved having to build giant long cables everywhere.</key>
    <value>DATURA:この種というやつは素晴らしい！とてつもなく長いケーブルをあちこちに作らなくて済むようになった。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: It’s pretty cool, huh?</key>
    <value>DATURA:なかなか格好いいじゃないか？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=orange&gt;WARNING:&lt;/color&gt; Coronal Mass Ejection!</key>
    <value>&lt;color=orange&gt;注意:&lt;/color&gt;コロナ質量放出！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=red&gt;ERROR:&lt;/color&gt; Gravity Stability System has been damaged!</key>
    <value>&lt;color=red&gt;エラー:&lt;/color&gt;重力安定化システムが損傷しています！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=orange&gt;WARNING:&lt;/color&gt; Giant's Deep approaching in &lt;TimeMinutesGDApproach&gt; MINUTES, &lt;TimeSecondsGDApproach&gt; SECONDS!</key>
    <value>&lt;color=orange&gt;注意:&lt;/color&gt;巨人の大海が接近するまで&lt;TimeMinutesGDApproach&gt;分&lt;TimeSecondsGDApproach&gt;秒！</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Bramble Station: End -->
  <!-- Initial Campsite: 1st House: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Landed! Dark Bramble. Kinda cool. Kinda... spooky.</key>
    <value>DATURA:着陸した！闇のイバラ、ちょっと格好いい。ちょっと…不気味な感じ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Hmm. There’s nothing edible here. I brought some supplies, the ice will be good for water, but these brambles (I imagine) will only be useful as a building material...</key>
    <value>DATURA:ふむ。ここには食べられるものがない。いくらか備えは持ってきていて、氷は水として使えるだろうが、イバラは(想像するに)建材としてしか使えないだろう…。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Well... This planet does have... anglerfish... in it... doesn’t it?</key>
    <value>DATURA:まぁ…この星には…アンコウが…いる…んだろう？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Not sure what I’m going to do with my shuttle. Suppose I’ll camp here for now. It’s actually quite nice! In this air pocket, anyway. Weird trees.</key>
    <value>DATURA:シャトルをどうするかは決めていない。とりあえずここでキャンプしてみるか。実に良い感じだ！このエアポケットではね。変な木がある。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Ugh. Yarrow... I know your intentions are good, but maybe it’s time to give up the obsession with the Eye. You know, the whole ’letting go’ thing everyone goes on about.</key>
    <value>DATURA:うぅ、Yarrow…。気持ちはわかるが、そろそろ眼への執着を捨てたらどうだろう。君も知っているだろう、皆が言う「手放す」ということを。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Jetpacking around this planet is quite fun! I should keep a couple eyes on my fuel, though.</key>
    <value>DATURA:この惑星をジェットパックで移動するのはとても楽しい！だが、燃料の残りを「2つ」の目は常に見続ける必要がある。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Last night, I had a dream of bridges connecting up all the ice islands... They were burning. And I was burning. But if I stay here a while, a non-burning variant could be useful.</key>
    <value>DATURA:昨晩、氷の島々を橋で繋ぐ夢を見た…。それは燃えていた。そして、俺も燃えていた。だが、しばらくここにいるならば燃えない変種が役に立つかもしれない。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Ahhh, this planet reminds me of one I went to with Filix. Gusty Gardens... Oh yeah, and Cosmic Cove! And...! Those... Those were good times.</key>
    <value>DATURA:あぁ、この惑星はかつてFilixと行ったところを思い出させる。突風の庭園…。そうそう、宇宙の入りえも！それから…！ あの頃は…あの頃は良い時代だった。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: But here I am on Dark Bramble! ...alone. ...Ugh, I have to focus. I’m on a mission!</key>
    <value>DATURA:だが俺はここ闇のイバラにいる！…独りで。…うっ、集中しなくては。俺には使命がある！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Here lies my first house. Murdered by Giant’s Deep.</key>
    <value>ここに最初の家がある。巨人の大海に大破させられたのだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Initial Campsite: 1st House: End -->
  <!-- Shuttle Crusher: Three Panels: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Right, the shuttle is just sitting here, and I can’t send it back without sending ME back, so...</key>
    <value>DATURA:さて、シャトルはここに置かれていて、俺が乗らないことには送り返せない。それなら…。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I’m gonna smash it to bits! It’ll be... symbolic.</key>
    <value>DATURA:粉々に砕いてやる！それは、…象徴的なことなんだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: You know, to say: I will not return until I have accomplished what I set out to do!</key>
    <value>DATURA:何しろ、次のように言うためだ:俺は、自分がやろうとしたことを成し遂げるまで帰らない！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Update: So... I did it, I suppose.</key>
    <value>DATURA:最新情報:そして…、やれてしまった、ようだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I used this smashy smashy device on the shuttle: which dented it, and set off the shuttle’s alarm, which was, well, alarming.</key>
    <value>DATURA:シャトルにこのスマッシュ、スマッシュな装置を使用した:シャトルはへこみ警報が、そう、警報が作動した。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: And the warp core fell out, so I went over to grab it - might be useful, I thought. But after returning to the shelter here to use the device a second time, the shuttle blew up!</key>
    <value>DATURA:するとワープコアが落ちたので取りに行った―役に立つかもしれないと思った。だが、装置を再び使おうとシェルターに戻ったところで、シャトルが吹っ飛んでしまった！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Mission accomplished. But also wow, I almost died! I should be more careful...</key>
    <value>DATURA:ミッションは達成した。しかし、もう少しで死ぬところだった！もっと気をつけないと…。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Update... again: I’ve set up a Projection Pool on the ice island west from here, so I can talk to Filix and my daughter.</key>
    <value>DATURA:最新情報…再び:ここから西にある氷の島にプロジェクションプールを設置し、Filixやむすめと話せるようにした。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: ...But instead, Bells and Pye called, informing me the <![CDATA[<color=lightblue>Gravity Cannons</color>]]> were improved a bit since I left - they, too, realised the issue of my shuttle being stuck here.</key>
    <value>DATURA:…しかし代わりに、BellsとPyeが通話をしてきて、俺が去った後に<![CDATA[<color=lightblue>重力砲</color>]]>が少し改良されたことを教えてくれた―彼らもまた、シャトルがここで待機したままになっている問題に気づいていた。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: They told me that they were trying to recall it from the <![CDATA[<color=lightblue>Gravity Cannon</color>]]>, but the switch they had added wasn’t working for some reason, and told me to check if there was something up with my shuttle... Hahaha... Uh... Whoops...</key>
    <value>DATURA:重力砲からそのシャトルを呼び戻そうとしたものの、その追加したスイッチがなぜか機能しなかったようで、俺にシャトルに何か異常がないか確認するようにとのことだった…。ははは…。うぅ、おっと…。</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Shuttle Crusher: Three Panels: End -->
  <!-- Shuttle Crusher: Crush Ship of Friend: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Aha! It would seem Friend enjoys some symbolism too!</key>
    <value>DATURA:なるほど！Friendもあの象徴的なものを楽しむときが来たようだ！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Friend asked why I've written and am writing my thoughts and leaving them around the place. I told them it's kinda a Nomai thing.</key>
    <value>DATURA:Friendがなぜ俺が自分の考えを書いて、あちこちに置いているのかと聞いてきた。これはNomaiのある種の風習なんだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Nomai are <![CDATA[<i>]]>(or are supposed to be)<![CDATA[</i>]]> nomads, so I suppose it's a way of telling other Nomai clans ’HA HA! We were here first!’</key>
    <value>DATURA:Nomaiはnomads、遊牧民である<![CDATA[<i>]]>(はず)<![CDATA[</i>]]>なので、おそらく他のNomai部族に「はは！俺たちが先に来たんだよ！」と言うためだったのではないかと思っている。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Or warn them of dangers or cool stuff or something.</key>
    <value>DATURA:もしくは危険なものとか格好いいものとか、そういうものを警告するためか。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Welp, time to destroy another ship! I used the machine just the once, which damaged their ship and caused the ship's alarm to go off. Remembering last time, I waited.</key>
    <value>DATURA:さぁ、別の船を破壊する時間だ！俺は一度だけあの機械を使ってアイツの船に損傷を与え、船の警報を響かせた。そうして前回のことを思い出しながら、待つことにした。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Friend was a bit confused why I wasn't using the device again, but I assured them I knew what I was doing. We waited... and waited... then, bang! Their ship exploded too. Then they understood.</key>
    <value>DATURA:Friendはなぜ俺が再び装置を使わないのか少し困惑していたが、俺は問題ないと断言した。俺たちは待っていた…、待っていた…、そしてバーンと音がした！アイツの船も爆発した。こうして何を待っていたのか理解してくれた。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Friend used to go off to their clan occasionally. Perhaps building a house here made it so they don't need to? Anyway, I'm glad you're here, Friend.</key>
    <value>DATURA:以前は、Friendは時々自分の一族のもとへ帰っていた。それがここに家を建てたことで、その必要がなくなったのだろうか？ともあれ、君がここにいてくれて嬉しいよ、Friend。</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Shuttle Crusher: Crush Ship of Friend: End -->
  <!-- Shuttle Crusher: Call to Solanum: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Hey little one! You’ll be off to the school on Brittle Hollow soon! (With no railings above a black hole.) I imagine you’ll be glad to get away from all this sand, eh?</key>
    <value>DATURA:もしもし、私の可愛いむすめよ！もうすぐ脆い空洞の学校へ移動する頃か！(ブラックホールの上に手すりがないけど。)砂だらけのところから離れられるのは嬉しいだろうね？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Yeah, but I don’t like that Mom is going to be the teacher!</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:うん、でもママが先生になるのは嫌だなぁ！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Hahaha. Sometimes I wonder if Filix is intentionally doing this to you. Hypothesis: much embarrassment awaits you.</key>
    <value>DATURA:ははは。Filixはわざとこうしてるんじゃないかなぁと思うことがあるよ。仮説:たくさんの恥ずかしさがSolanumを待っている。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Nooooooo! ...oh! I just remembered! I wanted to ask you about some things... The Eye? What is it? I keep hearing about it.</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:嫌だぁーーーー！…あ！そうそう思い出したんだけど！ちょっと聞きたいことがあって…、眼？あれは何？ずっと聞こうと思ってて。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Oh, uh. Right. Well, let’s see... Filix detected a signal on the Vessel - a signal from something older than the universe. Spooky. And we can’t find the signal anymore, so... I mean that’s it really.</key>
    <value>DATURA:あ、あー。そうだな、ふむ…。Filixは`船`である信号を検知した‐その信号は宇宙よりも古いというものだった。気味が悪いものだ。そして、その信号はもう見つかっていない。だから、…つまり、本当にそれだけなんだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: The Vessel. That was the other thing! What happened to the Vessel?</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:`船`。また別のものが出てきた！`船`はどうしてるの？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Oh... Darling, that’s... not a happy story. Another time, maybe.</key>
    <value>DATURA:あぁ…、可愛いむすめよ、それは…幸せなお話ではないよ。また、今度にしようか。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Aw! But I’m curious!</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:ああ！でも気になる！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: You’re curious, are you? Well, alright. But don’t tell your mother I didn’t warn you.</key>
    <value>DATURA:興味津々、かぁ。まあ、いいか。でも、お母さんには内緒にしておくように。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: So! I suppose I’ll tell it from my perspective. Ahem! I was once a crew member of: the Vessel - a moon-sized space ship capable of warping anywhere.</key>
    <value>DATURA:では！俺の目線で語ることにしよう。オホン！俺はかつて`船`のクルーだった‐これはどこにでもワープができる月サイズの宇宙船だったんだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I was reading in the library, when suddenly we warp! But, on our arrival there was a horrible screeching sound! We had crashed. I try to look for your mother, but I am forced onto an Escape Pod.</key>
    <value>DATURA:俺は図書室で本を読んでいた、そしたら突然ワープしたんだ！だが、到着した瞬間、ものすごい金切り声がした！墜落したんだ。お母さんを探そうとしたけれど、俺は脱出ポッドに押し込められた。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I landed on Ember Twin, and Filix landed on Brittle Hollow. Both groups had to rebuild to survive.</key>
    <value>DATURA:俺は燃え盛る双子星に、そしてFilixは脆い空洞に降り立った。2つのグループは双方ともに生き残るため再建を迫られた。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Many years passed until finally, a shuttle was sent from Brittle Hollow, and we were reunited. Us on Ember Twin were then told why we crashed, and about the Eye. After that, the... failed efforts to find the Eye began.</key>
    <value>DATURA:それから長い年月が経ち、ついに脆い空洞からシャトルが送られてきて、俺たちは再会することができた。そして墜落の理由と、眼のことを聞かされた。その後、眼を探すための…、失敗の日々が始まった。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Did everyone get to an escape pod?!</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:みんな脱出ポッドに乗れたの？！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Uh... not quite everyone. Only three of the five escape pods were launched.</key>
    <value>DATURA:うぅ…、全員というわけではない。5つの脱出ポッドのうち、たった3つしか発射されなかった。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Three? What happened to the third one?</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:3つ？3つ目はどうしたの？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Yeah, it... never got out of Dark Bramble.</key>
    <value>DATURA:ああ、それは…、闇のイバラから抜け出せなかったんだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Are they alright?</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:大丈夫なの？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Uh, maybe! We haven’t been able to contact them yet, if they are still al... alright.</key>
    <value>DATURA:ああ、多分！まだ連絡はとれてないが、もしまだ大…、大丈夫なら。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Oh...</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:あぁ…。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Well... I did warn you.</key>
    <value>DATURA:えぇと…、約束は覚えているね？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>FILIX: What are you two talking about?</key>
    <value>FILIX:2人とも何を話してるの？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>SOLANUM: Dad told me about how everyone died on the Vessel.</key>
    <value>SOLANUM:パパから、`船`でみんな死んじゃったって話を聞いたよ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Solanum! I did not say that!</key>
    <value>DATURE:Solanum！そんなことは言ってない！</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Shuttle Crusher: Call to Solanum: End -->
  <!-- Anglerfish Hunting Blind: Outside: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>Note to self: make tractor beams more accurate to save on jetpack fuel.</key>
    <value>自分へのメモ:ジェットパックの燃料を節約するために、トラクタービームの精度を上げること。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>Anglerfish Hunting Blind\\n(See, Cycad? I can make puns too!)</key>
    <value>アンコウハント&lt;i&gt;ウ&lt;/i&gt;の隠れ家\\n(見てるか、Cycad？俺だってダジャレが言えるんだぞ！)</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Anglerfish Hunting Blind: Outside: End -->
  <!-- Study Tower: Disturbing: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Well this is a potentially disturbing discovery...</key>
    <value>DATURA:ふむ、これは気になる発見かもしれない…。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I’ll have to see if I can confirm it in my &lt;color=orange&gt;Observatory&lt;/color&gt;... If this is what I think it is...</key>
    <value>DATURA:&lt;color=orange&gt;観測所&lt;/color&gt;で確認してみなくては…。もしもこれが俺の思うものなら…。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: No, surely it isn’t. It’s fine. Everything’s fine.</key>
    <value>DATURA:いや、きっとそんなことはない。問題ない。何も問題ないんだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: ...I should call my daughter...</key>
    <value>DATURA:…むすめに通話するべきだな…。</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Study Tower: Disturbing: End -->
  <!-- Study Tower: Spherical Region: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: After crashing on Ember Twin, I saw... something strange up in space. I kept it to myself as no-one else seemed to notice it. Too distracted on, uh, surviving, I suppose.</key>
    <value>DATURA:燃え盛る双子星に墜落した後、俺は…宇宙で何か奇妙なものを見た。誰も気づかなかったからか胸の内に秘めるだけにしていた。おそらく、ああ、生き残ることに集中しすぎたんだろう。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I’ve been attempting to locate what I saw. And hey, if I locate the Eye, then we can all return to our living quarters prematurely!</key>
    <value>DATURA:あのとき見たものを探そうとしている。そう、もし眼が見つかれば、皆早々に本来の居住区に帰れるからな！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: An update: I’ve found it?! There’s a spherical region in space where the stars occasionally... flicker. As if those stars are... fake?</key>
    <value>DATURA:最新情報:発見した？！宇宙空間に球状の領域があり、そこで星が時折…明滅している。その星はまるで…偽物？</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Study Tower: Spherical Region: End -->
  <!-- Study Tower: Meet Friend: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: WOAH! It appears we are not alone in this star system! Someone has just arrived here.</key>
    <value>DATURA:ワオッ！この星系には俺たちだけしかいないわけではないらしい！誰かがここにちょうど来たようだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: They sat on the walkway, and I sat with them, trying my best to comfort them - a happy person doesn’t come to Dark Bramble.</key>
    <value>DATURA:その人物はここの歩道に座っていた。俺はともに座り、できる限りなぐさめようとした―闇のイバラに来たのは幸せな者ではなかったのだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: It’s... nice to have company.</key>
    <value>DATURA:そう…仲間がいるのは嬉しいことだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I’m not sure how much we have in common, but I hope we can be friends.</key>
    <value>DATURA:どこまで俺たちに共通点があるかはわからないが、友人になれたら良いと思っている。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Update: Seems like they’re staying for a while! I’ll start building a house for them at the &lt;color=orange&gt;South Pole&lt;/color&gt;.</key>
    <value>DATURA:最新情報:どうやらしばらく留まるようだ！&lt;color=orange&gt;南極&lt;/color&gt;にさっそく家を作ろうと思う。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Before my clan crashed here, I had read about their species. If we could understand eachother’s languages, I’d love to hear their encounter with &lt;color=lightblue&gt;The Collector&lt;/color&gt; from their perspective.</key>
    <value>DATURA:俺たちの一族がここに墜落する前に、彼らの種族について読んだことがある。もし言葉が通じるなら、彼らの視点での&lt;color=lightblue&gt;収拾者&lt;/color&gt;との遭遇について聞いてみたいところだ。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: If it’s not a touchy subject, of course.</key>
    <value>DATURA:もちろん、もしも触れられないような内容でなければだけれど。</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Study Tower: Meet Friend: End -->
  <!-- Projection Pool House: Ash Projection Stone: Start -->
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Hello? Yarrow! There’s-</key>
    <value>DATURA:もしもし？Yarrow！そこに―</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>YARROW: Oh... hello. Hypothesis: Our failure with the Sun Station brought you here to ridicule me.</key>
    <value>YARROW:あぁ…もしもし。仮説:太陽ステーションでの失敗をきっかけに私を嘲笑いに来たのだろう。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;: Uh... Hypothesis: it would be beneficial to you both if neither of you called each other anymore.</key>
    <value>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;:うっ…仮説:もうお互いに通話しない方が2人のためになると思う。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: I... Yarrow, are you alright? Yarrow? Hey, wait!</key>
    <value>DATURA:私は…Yarrow、大丈夫か？Yarrow？おい、待てよ！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;: Oh, see you later, Yarrow! Don’t worry, we’ll figure it out! I believe in us! ...So, Datura, what is the true intent of your call?</key>
    <value>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;:あっ、またね、Yarrow！心配しないで、私たちは解決してみせる！そう信じてる！…それで、Datura、この通話の本当の目的は何ですか？</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>DATURA: Uh, th-there’s a comet coming! And it’s filled with-!</key>
    <value>DATURA:うぅ、す、彗星が来るんだ！しかも、その彗星には―！</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;: Oh, you observed the comet too? You and me both! We’ve actually already sent a shuttle to go check it out. But thanks anyway, Datura.</key>
    <value>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;:ああ、彗星も観測したんですね？私も同じくです！実はもうシャトルを送って確認に行ってるところなんです。でも、とにかくありがとう、Datura。</value>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <key>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;: Well, I’m gonna catch up to Yarrow to see if he’s alright. See ya around! Don’t be a stranger, now!</key>
    <value>&lt;color=brown&gt;SPIRE&lt;/color&gt;:さて、私はYarrowを捕まえて彼が大丈夫か確認してくるよ。ではまたね！よそよそしくなるな、ということ！</value>
  </entry>
  <!-- Projection Pool House: Ash Projection Stone: End -->
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Eye of the Universe</key>
    <value>宇宙の眼</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Cliffside Home</key>
    <value>崖上の家</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Northern Observatory</key>
    <value>北部観測所</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Study Tower</key>
    <value>研究塔</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Top of the Tower</key>
    <value>塔の最上部</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble Village</key>
    <value>イバラの村</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secret Room</key>
    <value>隠された部屋</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secluded Structure</key>
    <value>密閉された構造物</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Inside the Structure</key>
    <value>構造物の内側</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Shuttle Crusher</key>
    <value>シャトル破砕機</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool House</key>
    <value>プロジェクションプールの家</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Hunting Blind</key>
    <value>ハントの隠れ家</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>The Collector Mural</key>
    <value>収拾者の壁画</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Initial Campsite</key>
    <value>初期キャンプ場</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble Power Station</key>
    <value>イバラ動力ステーション</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble Power StationA power station that uses Bramble Seeds to connect all locations on Dark Bramble to a power source.</key>
    <value>イバラの種を利用し、闇のイバラのすべての拠点を動力源に接続するステーション。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble Power StationAccording to a Nomai computer, the ’Gravity Stability System’ has been disabled by a recent Coronal Mass Ejection from the sun that hit Dark Bramble.</key>
    <value>Nomaiのコンピュータによると、闇のイバラを最近襲った太陽からのコロナ質量放出により、重力安定化システムが無効化された。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble Power StationI used a switch to turn off power to one of the locations.</key>
    <value>私はスイッチで1か所の動力を切った。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble Power StationI fired a scout through a bramble seed and it exited out of another on Dark Bramble.</key>
    <value>イバラの種に偵察機を発射したところ、闇のイバラの別の場所に出た。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Initial CampsiteA campsite next to the Shuttle Crusher that I didn’t explore.</key>
    <value>シャトル破砕機の隣にあるキャンプ場をまだ探索していない。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Initial CampsiteWhere a Nomai named ’Datura’ first landed on Dark Bramble and set up camp.</key>
    <value>Daturaという名のNomaiが闇のイバラで最初に着陸し、キャンプ場とした場所。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Initial CampsiteFeldspar left a recording here saying they explored around and had ’some ideas’ on how to get into places, and offers his help if I want it.</key>
    <value>Feldsparは周辺を探索した。そして、いくつかの場所へ入るための「アイデア」があり、望むなら助言をするという記録を残した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Hunting BlindDatura, needing a food supply, considered eating... the Anglerfish.</key>
    <value>食料を必要とするDaturaは、...アンコウを食べることを考えた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Hunting BlindDatura went exploring the depths of Dark Bramble. Partly to find... food.</key>
    <value>Daturaは闇のイバラの内部を探索した。その目的は…食料を探すことだった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Hunting BlindDatura also discovered that Anglerfish are blind.</key>
    <value>Daturaはアンコウの目が見えないことも発見した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Hunting BlindOn telling the discovery to Yarrow, he was interested at first, but the conversation turned into a big argument.</key>
    <value>その発見をYarrowに話すとはじめは興味を持ってくれたが、話は次第に大きな論争へと至ってしまった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Hunting BlindDatura found the remains of the Nomai of Escape Pod 3, and his clan’s leader, Escall.</key>
    <value>Daturaは脱出ポッド3のNomaiと、彼の一族のリーダーであるEscallの遺体を発見した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Shuttle CrusherDatura landed on Dark Bramble in a shuttle, which he didn’t know what to do with.</key>
    <value>シャトルで闇のイバラに降り立ったDaturaは、シャトルをどうするか悩んだ。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Shuttle CrusherA Nomai called Datura created this to destroy his shuttle. After damaging the shuttle, its alarm went off, and exploded a while after.</key>
    <value>Daturaという名のNomaiが、自分のシャトルを破壊するために作ったものだ。シャトルに損傷を与えた後、警報が響き渡り、しばらくして爆発した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Shuttle CrusherSomeone referred to as ’Friend’ also wanted to destroy their ship. After damaging their ship, its alarm went off too. Datura remembered that he should just stand back and wait until it exploded.</key>
    <value>Friendと呼ばれる人物も、自らの船を破壊しようとしていた。その船に損傷を与えると、同じく警報が発せられた。Daturaは、このまま爆発するまで待機していれば良いのだと思い出した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Shuttle CrusherI used a switch to activate the crusher.</key>
    <value>私はスイッチで破砕機を作動させた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Shuttle CrusherIn a recording, Datura told his daughter Solanum about the Vessel crash.</key>
    <value>DaturaがむすめのSolanumに船の墜落のことを話している記録が残されていた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseA structure next to the Study Tower appears to have broken off and fallen into the planet somewhere.</key>
    <value>研究塔に隣接した建物の橋が折れ、この惑星のどこかに落下しているように見える。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseDatura built a projection pool on an island west of his landing site to be able to talk to his wife and daughter.</key>
    <value>Daturaはパートナーやむすめと話ができるよう、着陸地点の西にある島にプロジェクションプールを作った。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseDatura tried to leave Dark Bramble, but both shuttles were in use at that time.</key>
    <value>Daturaは闇のイバラから発とうとしたが、そのときシャトルは2台とも使用中だった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseDatura asked Bells to tell Solanum there was no need to rush, and to tell Filix that he was sorry and would see her again soon.</key>
    <value>DaturaはBellsに、Solanumには急ぐ必要はない、Filixには申し訳ない、すぐにまた会える、と伝えてほしいと頼んだ。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseIn a damaged stone, Datura called the others to warn them about something. But, they already knew about it.</key>
    <value>損傷したプロジェクションストーンにて、Daturaは何かを警告するために他のNomaiを呼んだ。しかし、彼らは既にそのことを知っているようだった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseIn the undamaged stone, Datura tried to warn the others about the Interloper. But, they already knew about it.</key>
    <value>損傷していないプロジェクションストーンにて、Daturaは侵入者について他のNomaiに警告しようとした。しかし、彼らは既にそのことを知っているようだった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Projection Pool HouseDatura and Solanum planned to meet after he had finished something, and after she had returned from the Quantum Moon.</key>
    <value>Daturaが何かを終え、そしてSolanumが量子の月から帰ってきた後に2人は合流するつもりだった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Study TowerA Nomai named Datura discovered a spherical region in space where the stars flickered occasionally.</key>
    <value>Daturaという名のNomaiは、時折星が明滅する球状の領域が宇宙空間に存在することを発見した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Study TowerUpon meeting a being from another species, Datura helped build them a house at the South Pole.</key>
    <value>異種族と出会ったDaturaは、南極に家を建てる手伝いをした。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Study TowerDatura discovered something that disturbed him, but he had to go his Observatory to confirm it.</key>
    <value>Daturaは気になることを発見したが、それを確認するために観測所へ向かわなければならなかった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Top of the TowerThe stairs to the top of the Study Tower have collapsed.</key>
    <value>研究塔の最上部への階段は崩壊している。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Top of the TowerI can see a wall with Nomai text through the window.</key>
    <value>窓からNomaiの文字が書かれた壁が見える。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Top of the TowerDatura added a second security measure to his Observatory. The door will remain shut if another space ship is on Dark Bramble’s surface.</key>
    <value>Daturaは観測所に2つ目のセキュリティ対策を施した。闇のイバラの地表に他の宇宙船がある場合、その扉は閉じたままとなる。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageUpon meeting a being from another species, Datura helped build them a house at the South Pole.</key>
    <value>異種族と出会ったDaturaは、南極に家を建てる手伝いをした。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageDatura built a shelter for himself at the south pole.</key>
    <value>Daturaは南極に自分のための居住地を作った。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageDatura teached Friend the Nomai language, and they teached him art.</key>
    <value>DaturaはFriendにNomaiの言語を教え、Friendは彼に芸術を教えた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageDatura argued at Yarrow that they should be finding a way to leave this star system. Datura, promising Filix he would return, left to Dark Bramble to find the Vessel.</key>
    <value>DaturaはYarrowに、この星系を離れる方法を探すべきだと主張した。DaturaはFilixに必ず戻ると約束し、船を見つけるために闇のイバラへ向かった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageDatura is pessimistic about the Eye, and believes it will destroy the universe if someone interacts with it.</key>
    <value>Daturaは宇宙の眼について悲観的であり、誰かが眼に触れれば宇宙が破壊されると信じている。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageFriend is optimistic about the Eye, and believes it is the creator of universes.</key>
    <value>Friendは宇宙の眼について楽観的であり、眼は宇宙の創造者であると信じている。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Bramble VillageIn Friend’s House, I found a staircase that leads down abruptly to a painting of a terrestrial world, with a blue ringed gas giant in the sky.</key>
    <value>Friendの家にて、空に環を持つガス惑星が描かれている地上世界の壁画に向かって不意に伸びている階段を見つけた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secret RoomA secret room in Friend’s House contains an image revealing a hidden path behind a jellyfish surrounded by ice.</key>
    <value>Friendの家の隠された部屋には、氷に囲まれたクラゲの奥の秘められた道を示す映像がある。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secluded StructureA secret room in Friend’s House contains an image revealing a hidden path behind a jellyfish surrounded by ice.</key>
    <value>Friendの家の隠された部屋には、氷に囲まれたクラゲの奥の秘められた道を示す映像がある。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secret RoomDatura and Friend discussed their theories about the Eye, and suggested that they may both be partially true.</key>
    <value>DaturaとFriendは宇宙の眼についてのそれぞれの説を議論し、どちらも部分的に真実である可能性を示唆した。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secluded StructureThe entrance to this building appears to have been sealed. Datura theorised that only an explosion could create an opening.</key>
    <value>この建物の入口は封じられているようだ。Daturaは、爆発でも起こらなければ開口部は作れないと考えた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Secluded StructureIf I want to return here, I should use the Mark Location on HUD feature, like Slate told me about.</key>
    <value>ここに戻りたいなら、Slateに教えてもらったようにHUDに位置をマークする機能を使うべきだろう。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Inside the StructureI found the remains of Friend... holding an artifact next to a green fire.</key>
    <value>Friendの遺体を見つけた…。みどり色の火のそばで遺物を持っていた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Inside the StructureDatura was curious what Friend was hiding from him and sneaked here. He found an artifact and green fire, tripped and knocked himself out, awaking on what appeared to be a different planet.</key>
    <value>DaturaはFriendが何を隠しているのか気になり、ここに忍び込んだ。彼は遺物とみどり色の火を見つけ、つまずいて気を失うと、別の惑星のような場所で目覚めた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Inside the StructureDatura came across Friend’s elders, and accidentally rang an alarm bell which woke one up.</key>
    <value>DaturaはFriendの長老に出くわした。また、誤ってベルを響かせ1人を目覚めさせてしまった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Inside the StructureHe was awoken by Friend, with some others having arrived on Dark Bramble.</key>
    <value>彼はFriendに起こされた。そこには闇のイバラに到着した流れ者の住人達がいた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Inside the StructureThey separated them from each other, containing Friend by sealing the entrance.</key>
    <value>彼らは互いに引き離され、Friendは入口を閉ざされて封印された。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Cliffside HomeI found... the remains of Friend, holding an artifact next to a green fire.</key>
    <value>Friendの遺体を見つけた…。みどり色の火のそばで遺物を持っていた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Cliffside HomeI met Friend! They had to communicate using the Nomai language, as I can’t translate theirs.</key>
    <value>Friendに会った！私が流れ者の言語を翻訳できないため、FriendはNomaiの言語を用いて意思伝達をしてくれた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Cliffside HomeFor one of the security measures, Datura used a quantum shard to effect the Northern Observatory’s door, so I must not be looking at the door when entering.</key>
    <value>セキュリティ対策の1つとして、Daturaは北部観測所の扉に量子のかけらを利用している。ゆえに、入るときは扉を見てはいけない。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Cliffside HomeThe Prisoner released the Eye’s signal briefly and was contained in the simulation. He was planned to be released into just the simulation with the others.</key>
    <value>囚人は眼の信号を一時的に解放し、それから模擬現実に収容された。いずれは囚人も他の住人達と一緒に、模擬現実内ではあるものの解放される予定だった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Cliffside HomeBy the time the Nomai arrived, Friend’s elders had ’decayed’ into the simulation. Only a small group of the youngest were still alive outside.</key>
    <value>Nomaiが到着したときには、Friendの長老達は模擬現実内で朽ち果てた状態になっていた。外で生きているのは、ごく一部の最も若い住人達だけだった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>The Collector MuralDatura mentioned something called ’The Collector,’ but didn’t elaborate.</key>
    <value>Daturaは収拾者と呼ばれるものに言及したが、詳しくは語らなかった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>The Collector MuralA mysterious planet that spewed out a deadly substance that was contained in water worlds and comets.</key>
    <value>水の世界や彗星に含まれる致死性の物質を噴出した謎の惑星。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Northern ObservatoryThere’s an Observatory on Dark Bramble’s north pole with two security measures keeping the door shut.</key>
    <value>闇のイバラの北極に観測所があり、2つのセキュリティ対策により扉は閉じられている。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Northern ObservatoryDatura discovered something that disturbed him, but he had to go his Observatory to confirm it.</key>
    <value>Daturaは気になることを発見したが、それを確認するために観測所へ向かわなければならなかった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Northern ObservatoryI found Datura’s body...</key>
    <value>Daturaの遺体を発見した…。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Northern ObservatoryAt his projection pool, Datura attempted to warn the others of the Interloper, but they already knew about it.</key>
    <value>プロジェクションプールでは、Daturaは他のNomaiに侵入者のことを警告しようとしたが、彼らは既にそのことを知っているようだった。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Northern ObservatoryDatura was able to get Solanum to be at the Quantum Moon’s sixth location as the Interloper arrived.</key>
    <value>Daturaは、侵入者が到着したときに、Solanumがちょうど量子の月の第6の場所にいるように仕向けることができた。</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Eye of the UniverseThe Eye. Is it a creator or a destroyer of universes? ...Do I want to find out?</key>
    <value>宇宙の眼。それは果たして宇宙の創造者なのか、それとも破壊者なのか？…私はそれを見極めようか？</value>
  </table_shipLog>
  <table_shipLog>
    <key>Eye of the UniverseIf you are reading this, I assume you have gotten inside the Northern Observatory and have seen the new ending at the Eye. Thank you so much for playing The Outsider! I hope you enjoyed it!</key>
    <value>もしこれを読んでいるなら、北部観測所内部に入り、そして宇宙の眼で新たなエンディングを見たのでしょう。 Thank you so much for playing The Outsider! I hope you enjoyed it!</value>
  </table_shipLog>
</TranslationTable_XML>
